Thomas J Lazore

Software Developer

Address Savannah, United States, 31410

Phone 315-778-6632

E-mail tomlazore@gmail.com

Full Stack software developer with a certificate from Georgia Tech Coding Boot Camp. Working with technologies such as JavaScript, Express, and Node in the development of group and solo projects. Past relevant experience involve a research assistant internship developing the front-end of a project for Rochester Institute of Technology. A leadership background as a paramedic has developed skills to be an effective and resourceful team member as well as independent worker.

Projects

Never Alone

github.com/tlaze/NeverAlone | never-alone-platform.herokuapp.com/

- **Description:** Team of 4 members developing a social media website geared towards mental health.
- **Responsibilities:** Creation, editing, and deletion of posts | Making the application mobile responsive.
- **Technology Used:** HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Javascript | Node | Express | Handlebars | Express-Session | MySQL2 | Sequelize | Connect-Session-Sequelize | Heroku | Nodemailer

Tech Blog

github.com/tlaze/tech-blog | cryptic-thicket-49114.herokuapp.com/

- **Description:** Forum based application for creating posts, updating, and deleting posts.
- **Technology Used:** HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Javascript | Node | Express | Handlebars | Express-Session | MySQL2 | Sequelize | Connect-Session-Sequelize | Heroku

Weather Dashboard

github.com/tlaze /weather-dashboard | tlaze.github.io /weather-dashboard/

- **Description:** Fetches data from a third party API to display current and future weather conditions for cities that users enter.
- Technology Used:

HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Javascript | JQuery | OpenWeatherOneAPI | Local Strorage

Education

2021-09 - 20212 Full Stack Coding Boot Camp

Georgia Institute of Technology - Atlanta, GA

2018-09 - Computer Science

2019-09 Monroe Community College - Rochester, NY

- Relevant Coursework Completed: Intro to Computer Science with Java & Programming with Python
- Completed a summer internship with Rochester Institute of Technology working on the front-end development of an application that recognizes handwritten mathematical formulas and converts it into searchable queries.

Work History

2020-03

2019-08

2017-09 - Paramedic

Irondequoit Ambulance, Irondequoit, NY

- Triaged injuries by communicating with patients, bystanders and family members, and identified appropriate medical facility for transport.
- Used EMSCharts to accurately document services provided to reduce liability and improve patient care.
- Trained EMTs in basic life support skills, oxygen therapy, and wound care.
- Communicated with hospital personnel and dispatchers to provide information about situation, arrange reception of victims and receive instructions for further treatment.

2019-05 - Research Assistant Intern

Rochester Institute Of Technology, Rochester, NY

- Prepared materials for submission to agencies and foundations to fund research.
- Researched and interpreted large volumes of scientific data and literature about search interfaces and indexing mathematical formulas.
- Used Zotero to prepare articles, reports and presentations.
- Presented technical research results to diverse audiences through written, visual and oral media.